Yes, believe your eyes.
Those are the northern lights...
on view above the city
for the first time in nearly 80 years.
It's 5:00 a.m. Hello, New York.
The big story this morning...
is the Amazins taking
the field today in Baltimore...
for their final practice
before tomorrow's opener...
of the 1969 World S...
Sanitation workers discovered the
dead body of another nurse in Queens.
This is the third nurse killed in what
New York papers are now calling...
the 'Nightingale Murders.'
All three victims have been nurses,
each found strangled...
with their hands gruesomely bound
behind their backs with tape.
The lights, also known
as the aurora borealis...
Look out.
Move it.
Manhattan calling Eye of the Storm.
Engine Company 12,
Ladder Company 93...
respond to Manhattan box 132 off-ramp
of the George Washington Bridge.
On our way.
Confirm overturned tanker. Workers
trapped in underground substation.
Frank. We're second in.
We got the rescue.
- Okay.
Commander, what do you need done?
That dike's about to go, and we're
one spark away from losing the block.
Is there another way in?
- That manhole leads to the vault.
Forget it, Sullivan.
Vault door's rusted shut,
and they can't kill the juice.
Isn't enough time to make it.
What? Miss the World Series?
Not a chance. Gimme my tools.
Sullivan. This is Commander O'Connell.
Can you hear me?
I hear you, Commander.
- The gasoline is risin' in the vault.
Those downed cables hit that gas,
it's gonna blow.
Way to go, Gib.
- I shoulda been a goddamn mailman.
Clear this channel.
Explosion's imminent.
Hey, guys.
Can you hear me?
Yeah, we're in here.
- We're comin' in.
Get us outta here.
He's got a broken leg.
Get us out.
It's gonna flash. Get outta there.
Dike isn't holdin'.
Get us out.
- Frank, do you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you, Butch.
Grab that ax.
- Here.
Gimme a whack. No sparks. Again.
One more.
Okay, stand back.
Oh, thank God.
Oh. Yeah, my leg's all busted up.
Please hurry.
- We're in, Butch.
Get 'em and get the hell out.
Hey, fellas, time to go home.
Watch it, watch it.
It's gone. It's gonna break.
- Back, back. Let's go.
That's an order.
Everybody goes.
All right, let's move
before the gas lights up.
Watch that wire.
Get out, for Christ's sake.
I gotcha.
Butch, Butch,
we're comin' out right now.
Go.
- You all right? Watch your head.
Get up that ladder.
Go ahead.
Get up, get up.
Go on up.
Go. Right behind you.
Keep going.
Pull him out.
Come on. Come on, come on.
I gotcha. I gotcha.
Welcome to the company, Gib.
Hey, fellas.
Hey, Dad.
- Hey. Hey, Gordo.
Hey, Mr. Sullivan.
- How you doin'?
How's my Little Chief, huh?
- Good.
Where's your mother?
- Inside the house.
'October 10th 1969'
Hey, Jules.
Hey, bud.
- Hey, bud.
That was 'Heat Wave.' Martha and
the Vandellas on WOR New York radio.
Hey, how about a little
bit of the King, huh?
Yeah, why not a little of the King?
Damn.
- You all right?
Yeah. I think I ruined the sauce.
Again.
What's the matter, bud?
You havin' trouble working
an eight-hour shift at the hospital...
watchin' the kid,
whippin' up a little Bolognese?
You didn't marry Donna Reed.
- Hey.
I'd go for you and Chinese takeout
over her any day.
Because I love you too much
Baby
Why can't you see...
What you're doin' to me
- How was your tour?
The usual. You know.
Butch called.
- Did he?
He did.
It was under control, bud.
Butchy, he's gettin' a little tight
in his old age.
Nothing wrong with old age, Frank.
Long as you get there.
All right, Chief, when I let go,
I want you to keep peddling.
Daddy, put the wheels back on.
I'm gonna fall.
Don't worry about falling.
You're ready to do this.
Come on. Spirit and guts, okay?
All right. Keep pedalin'.
I'm gonna let go.
That's it.
Keep pedalin'.
Keep pedalin', keep pedalin'.
Yeah.
Ow.
- You all right? You all right?
No, Dad.
- Johnny.
You okay? You hurt? You okay?
I wanna go to my room.
- Okay. Go on, honey. It's okay.
Hey, come on, Chief.
Don't quit on me now.
Don't be so tough on him, Frank.
He's just a kid.
He just needs to know you're behind him.
Okay. You're right.
All right.
CQ-22, this is W-2-QYV,
by for call.
Because of the solar activity.
Yeah, it's beautiful. We got the sky
over my house lit up like a bonfire.
Word is the sunspots
are shooting off flares...
that stretch out half
a million kilometers.
Tell me about it. I'm pickin' up signals
from places I could never reach before.
Francis, is that you?
How are you doing?
Hey, I'm doing just great.
How you doing?
Fantastic. My wife, Sophia,
she's gonna give me another baby.
Wow.
'October 10th 1999'
So, that's it, Samantha?
You're just walkin' out?
I've been walkin' out for six months, John.
You just didn't notice or care.
You were right.
We shoulda quit a long time ago.
I'm sorry. I know it's my fault.
I can't change, Sam.
I wish I could, but I can't.
John, it's that you won't change.
And that's what hurts so much.
Good-bye, Chief.
Next up, Johnny Sullivan.
It's a hit up the middle.
Johnny's gonna hold at first.
And now batting for Johnny's father,
Coach Newman.
Checks the runner and fires.
Lined hard to right.
No problem. One on, one out.
- Hi, Uncle John.
I'm not your uncle, kid.
- Hey, Sully, is that you?
Gordo, why are you guys in my house?
- My TV's out again.
Hey, uh, you want a brewski?
- Yeah.
Deep fly ball into center field.
- Do you believe Linda...
still won't let me cook in the house?
I melt one lousy frying pan.
- John, guess what.
Dad's takin' me fishin'. Wanna come?
- I wish I could, Gordy.
But you bring me back a big one, okay?
Is it okay if Gordy uses your old gear?
- Yeah, I think it's in the hall closet.
If you can find it.
- Gordy, have a look, huh?
So Yahoo went up
another five points today.
Man, did I miss the boat on that one.
- Shoulda, woulda, coulda, pal.
So Sam called Linda.
Dad, John, come here.
What are you doin' back there?
Dad, check it out.
- Wow.
Fire department.
Can I open it up?
Sure.
Whoa.
- Eh, eh, eh, gimme that gun.
All right?
Hey, what's this, Dad?
- Oh, my God.
John, it's your dad's old ham radio.
Remember how we used to beg him
to let us talk on this thing?
This is not a toy.
- Is not a toy.
Can we try it, Dad?
- Ask Uncle John.
Can we try it?
- What the hell.
All right.
Let's grab this baby out.
This is what we used when I was your age.
Let's go over to the den, huh?
Plug it in, just like old times.
We want CW or LSB.
Standby function. Operator, come on.
I don't know what's goin' on.
Let's take a look under the hood, huh?
See what we got here.
Check this baby out.
There she is.
So this is what people used
before the Net, huh?
Well, not exactly. I'll tell ya.
Hams were...
Ah, bingo.
These babies were different.
Not everybody had one of these...
and you needed a special license
just to be able to talk on 'em.
Damn. I just... I just...
I don't think it's gonna work here.
- It's junk, kid.
Nobody uses those things any more.
Gordo. Do you know what time it is?
Hey, John.
Hi, Linda.
- Come on, Gordy, let's go.
I'll catch you later, all right?
If I'm lucky.
So feed him.
Put it down there for him.
I'm not gonna speak
if you continue to say that word.
Hi, this is Julia Sullivan.
Please leave a message after the tone.
Hey, Ma, it's me.
Just checkin' in.
You're probably at work.
Anyways, um, I'll see you tomorrow night.
My grandmother was senile.
- Love you.
She had such fun on her birthdays.
She'd open her presents...
and drift off, then look down,
see her present and get happy again.
That's what my father does
with his breakfast cereal.
The aurora borealis,
to anyone who's seen it...
is one of the stunning events
of your lifetime.
They're brighter these days.
Is something going on there?
Do they tie in with your field?
Where do they come from?
It's a stunning sight.
It's beautiful to look at.
I don't think we've seen one
quite this bright for maybe 30 years.
But, from the point of view of physics
and string theory...
there's nothing really that we gain...
from studying the aurora borealis.
Now history does teach us every time
we thought we had it figured out...
there was some major discovery
right around the bend...
that required a dramatic change in our
understanding of the laws of physics.
This is a phrase people have begun
to hear... string theory.
Yes. Yes, that's right.
String theory dramatically changes...
our understanding of space and time.
For example, string theory requires
our universe to have ten...
or possibly even eleven dimensions.
And the strange thing is some physicists
are even pursuing the idea...
that there might be
more than one time dimension.
So, in addition to time as we know it,
psychological time...
which seems to organize events...
- CQ-15, W-2-QYV, by for call.
CQ-15, CQ-15, come in, 15.
Uh, hello?
Hey, W-2-QYV here.
Who have I got?
Name's John.
License to broadcast, buddy?
Look, I really don't remember
how this thing works.
Listen, you can't broadcast
without a license.
Unless this is an emergency,
you're gonna have to get off the band.
Hey, pal, my whole life's an emergency.
Where you transmittin' from?
Queens, New York.
Well, what do you know?
Bayside, born and raised.
No kidding? I thought these things
were for talking around the world.
Yeah, well, the 15 band closes down
at night...
but during the day you can chew
the band with China if you want.
I can't believe people are still
using these things.
You must be a real old-timer, huh?
- Days like this...
I feel like I'm gettin' there,
you know?
So, Queens, you psyched
for the Series, huh?
You know, I really don't follow
baseball any more.
What?
I got fed up with all the bullshit.
- What are you talkin' about?
Let me tell you,
a thousand years from now...
when school kids study
about America...
they're gonna learn about three things:
The Constitution, rock and roll...
and baseball.
How can you live in Queens
and not love the Amazins?
The Amazin' Mets?
What, the '69 Series?
Man, I'll love Ron Swoboda
till the day I die.
Well, now I'm with ya.
He's got the heart of a lion.
Mets can't win game one without him.
Can you hear me?
- Game one? What are you talkin' about?
It was all over after Buford nailed
Seaver's second pitch outta the park.
Hey, no way, buddy. Ain't gonna happen.
Hey, CQ-15. CQ-15.
Are you there?
Who the hell was that?
Queens? Are you there, Queens?
Did I lose ya?
Hey, Frank, give the radio a rest.
Your son wants to say good night.
All right, I'll be right there.
Elvis, you all right?
Oh, sorry.
You okay, Frank?
- We're fine. You all right?
You okay, buddy?
The sunspots are going to have
a serious impact...
on radio communication
for the next six or seven days.
In fact, quantum theory tells us
the rigid notions...
of past, present and future,
although useful in day-to-day life...
may dissolve and be replaced
by a complex formulation...
in which time is far more fluid
than anybody would have imagined.
Take me out to the ball game
Take me out with the crowd
Buy me some peanuts and Cracker Jack
I don't care if I never get back...
'Cause it's root, root, root
For the home team
If we don't win
Two, three strikes you're out
At the old ball game
You got it. That's perfect.
Hey, Butch, you gotta turn the whole set.
Can't wait till the game.
It's not the tuner,
it's the antenna.
Proby.
- What?
Point the antenna out
from under the house a little bit.
There it is.
Hey.
I'm gonna get a beer. Want one?
- Yeah, yeah.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Proby, walk away.
Walkin' away.
- If it ain't broke, don't fix it.
Here we go, Butch. Here we go.
- Hey, Satch. Grab a seat. Come on.
Sully, I think I need to get a new set
of cleats. I lost my footing there.
Yeah. Yeah.
Right.
- Dr. DeLeon, you decided to join us.
You don't wanna know.
Thirty-six hours,
I was bouncing off the walls.
That's why you're the doctor
and I'm the nurse.
Hey, baby. Can I get you something?
- No, it's all right.
I am starving.
- I'm ready.
Sit down.
How you boys doin'?
- Good, Satch.
Okay, I got something for you.
- I can't believe it.
And I got something for you.
- Whoa.
Dad, look.
- What? You gotta be...
Hey, Satch, you Santa Claus?
Game three tickets.
Did you say thank you or what?
Thank you, Uncle Satch.
- You're welcome.
Thank you. Thank you, Satch.
Hey, hey, all right, wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Everybody.
Everybody say, 'Amazin' Mets.'
- Amazing Mets.
Don't choke on your pride, Sull.
You ain't never gonna find
another one like Sam.
She made up her mind, Satch.
Nothin' I do is gonna change it.
Nothin' you're willing to do.
- What's the story?
Construction crew found a body,
actually, a skeleton.
Okay. Well, be real careful
when you pull it out.
Make sure you get the dirt around it.
- Yes, sir.
So, what's this construction?
- I think I'll visit the neighbors.
Yeah, okay.
What did they tear down here?
- Greek diner.
Used to get breakfast
there all the time.
Them Greeks were good people.
Careful. It's hot.
- Thank you, Mrs. Shepard.
Once that McDonald's opened up on
Dyckman, they lost all their business.
I see your son's on the job.
- Was.
Jack died a while back.
It's hard, I know.
It just seems like yesterday.
My son lived and bled blue.
I wanna get outta here.
- Okay, Detective.
Give my regards to Steph.
- Sure will.
This isn't gonna be anything
but a history lesson.
Let's go back to the house.
Hey, Barney. How you doin'?
- Good.
There you go. Have a good night.
- Bye.
I thought it'd be nicer to eat here.
- Hey, sounds good.
I'm sorry Samantha couldn't make it.
Yeah, those grad school applications
are drivin' her crazy.
How's it comin'?
- I got the VCR hooked up.
It's just this friggin' clock.
Doesn't matter.
Goddamn it. I'm sorry, Mom.
- Hey, you know, it's all right.
I'm sure everything'll work out.
- What's that?
With Sam.
- Oh, yeah, you know...
just a tough time right now,
you know.
So how are things at the hospital?
- Fine.
Hey, Dr. Schwartz retired last month.
- No kidding.
He must've been pushing 90.
- Close, yeah.
So, how'd you like The Lion King?
Oh, I loved it, you sweet kid.
I wish you'd gone.
Yeah, I know, I'm sorry.
It's just work.
Yeah, well, you work too hard.
Look who's talkin'.
It's tomorrow.
- Thirty years.
I wish I could remember him better.
He was just a big kid.
He wanted to play baseball forever.
And fighting fires, he loved that.
And you... he loved you.
Okay, guys, bedtime.
- Okay, Mom.
Looking good.
We'll do it again tomorrow, Chief.
Good night, Dad.
CQ-15, CQ-15.
W- 2-QYV...
calling unidentified
station, Queens.
CQ-15, W-2-QYV...
calling unidentified
station, Queens.
CQ-15. Come in, Queens.
- Hello.
Hey, hey, is that you? I've been tryin'
to Q you all night. Where you been?
Hey, I...
How the hell did you do it?
Do what?
- Do what? The Series.
You called Buford's homer.
How the hell did you do it?
It wasn't too tough, buddy,
the game happened 30 years ago.
Yeah, right, right, yeah.
Thirty years ago. Yeah, sure.
So I suppose you could tell me
what happened in game two, huh?
Yeah, sure. Top of the ninth.
Al Weis, game-winning RBI single.
Brooks Robinson grounds out
to end the game.
Daddy, come up and sing
the baseball song.
Hey, Little Chief.
You all right?
Well, you just go on up.
I'll be there in a minute, all right?
All right.
Sorry about that. That was my kid.
- What'd you just say?
I said, sorry about that.
My kid just came in.
You call your son 'Little Chief'?
- Yeah.
What'd you say your name was?
Frank. Frank Sullivan.
Is this some kind of joke? Gordo,
is that you? Are you messing with me?
No, I ain't messin' with you.
Look, I'm just tryin' to figure out...
You're tellin' me your name is
Frank Sullivan, you live in Queens...
and you wanna know how I called
the first game of the 1969 World Series?
Yeah, that's exactly what I wanna know.
Gordo, if this is you, so help me.
What'd you say your...
What'd you say your call station...
or your call letters were?
W- 2-QYV.
Now you listen to me.
My name is John Francis Sullivan.
I live at 34342nd Avenue,
where I lived my whole life...
and I saw the first game
of the 1969 World Series right here...
in this house 30 years ago.
- Bullshit.
My father's name is
Francis Patrick Sullivan.
He was a firefighter
and a die-hard Mets fan...
and every night when I went to bed,
he sang, 'Take Me Out to the Ball Game.'
Hey, who the hell are you?
Son of a bitch.
What's goin' on?
- Nothin's goin' on.
Oh, my God.
You burnt the desk.
I can see it.
Are you still there?
I said, you burnt the desk.
I can see it. Hello?
Hello? Are you still there?
Come back. Talk to me.
Hello?
Hey, hey, listen to me.
You listen to me right now.
I don't know who you are.
I don't know why you're doing this.
But let me tell you something,
asshole.
You stay away from me and my family.
No, no, no, you gotta believe me.
I don't know how this is happening,
but it's me, Little Chief.
Hey, hey, hey, look, look,
I am warning you.
If you touch my kid, I will hunt you
down till the day I die. You got that?
But you already died.
What are you talkin' about?
The Buxton fire.
Oh, yeah?
And when did that happen?
Thirty years ago?
October 12, 1969.
Tomorrow.
You're tellin' me I'm gonna d...
Look, I ain't dyin' in no fire tomorrow
or any other day, you got that?
Listen, tomorrow hasn't happened.
That's right, it hasn't happened.
It ain't gonna happen.
You gotta listen to me.
It was an abandoned warehouse.
Butch always told Ma it wasn't your
fault. You went with your instincts.
I'm warning you.
- Listen to me.
If you'd gone the other way,
you would've made it.
Hello?
Hello? Shit.
Sully, what are you doing, man?
- I talked to him. I talked to my dad.
Sull, go in the house, all right?
I'm gonna come over, we'll hang out.
No, no, no, I gotta get him back
so he doesn't go in.
Go in? What are you...
Go in where?
The warehouse in Buxton.
It's tomorrow.
Yeah, right, right, yeah.
Thirty years ago? Yeah, sure.
So I suppose you can tell me
what happened in game two, huh?
Yeah, sure. Top of the ninth,
Al Weis, game-winnin' RBI single.
Come on, hit it out.
- Come on, Al.
One run.
- Look at the stats. Look at them.
Let's go, Weis.
We have a three and two response,
Ladder 93.
You're first due. It's reported to be
an abandoned warehouse...
at the foot of Water
Street and Third.
Now, you got some construction
limiting access.
Al Weis is having a great Series.
Yeah, they won.
You all right?
We know it's vacant.
Nobody goes in.
Surround and drown.
Call for a tower.
Help.
- Shit. We got squatters inside.
Help me. My sister's...
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
She's up there. She passed out.
- Where is your sister?
I tried to help her.
- Tell me. What floor?
She's up there on the top floor.
I tried, I tried.
Please, help her. Please.
- Butch, take her.
Come on, follow me.
Anybody else up there?
Ryan, get her medical treatment.
Gimme my gear.
- You have fire in the top floor.
Yeah, these are good.
Hey, Sull.
Hey, here he is. How you feelin'?
- What can I tell you?
Here you go.
- Thanks. Better.
No visible fire first or second floor.
Watch your step, Proby.
This floor's rotten.
Fire on the third floor.
We need a line. We're goin' up.
We got two lines comin'.
Back out, kid. Wait for the line.
- To hell with the line.
I'll find another way up.
- No, you can't help me here.
So you doin' okay, John?
You know, tough day, you know?
Hey, here's to your dad, huh?
Thirty years today.
To your dad.
To my dad.
We're pullin' everyone outta the building.
Get that ladder on the top floor.
It's cooking up here.
So after that Halloween thing
with the fire truck... You remember?
Yeah, I remember riding
with Butch and your dad...
and the whole
neighborhood was watching.
I remember.
I wanted to go as a cop.
Yeah, so Jules makes your dad
buy you that...
that cop kit for your birthday.
- Oh, I remember that.
I was always the robber.
I was always being handcuffed.
That's right.
I taught you to do that.
10-45, I found the girl.
She's breathin'.
- We're gettin' 'em out.
Hang on.
What the hell is goin' on?
Gino, what's the matter?
- The gear box, it's cracked.
Frank, the ladder's jammed.
You gotta find another way out.
Frank, can you hear me?
It worked out okay, though.
You're a better cop than a fireman.
No doubt about it.
- Worked out good for me too.
I'm glad I didn't have to spend
ten years as his hose man.
Yeah, I bet you are.
The Buxton fire.
If you'd just gone the other way.
Frank, we're losin' the building.
I know.
Hey, hey, this is not a toy.
Wave to your ma.
- Look at us.
You're gonna be some ball player.
Whoa. John, are you all right?
- John, John.
I'm sorry.
- What is it?
Is everything okay?
- Yeah, can you bring a towel?
Satch, my father didn't
die in a fire, right?
Gordo, my father didn't die in a fire.
No. What are you talking about?
He had cancer.
Cancer because of his cigarettes, right?
The cigarettes?
Yeah. Lung cancer. Ten years ago.
Little Chief.
Gordo, I ain't dreamin' here.
I talked to him. It was real.
Little Chief.
John, what are you talkin' about?
- It was the ham radio.
That's how come he didn't die.
Little Chief.
John. John Sullivan,
are you there?
Come on, answer me.
Chief. Chief, are you there?
I'm right here, Daddy.
Come here.
Come on.
Where's Elvis?
- Sleepin'.
Sleepin'. Why aren't you sleepin'?
- You woke me up.
I did?
Hey, I got an idea.
- What's that?
All right, Chief.
What do you say
we tame this bronco, huh?
I'm scared.
- I know.
And you know what?
I'm gonna be right here with you.
Always.
Daddy, I can't.
Well, we can.
We can do it together.
You and me, spirit and guts.
What do you say?
Okay.
- All right, come on.
Now you just take your time. I'm not
gonna let go until you say it's okay.
Okay.
- All right? Start pedaling.
That's it. Get your balance.
Ready? Okay, I'm still here.
- Wait.
Okay.
- All right.
It's all you.
- Look at me.
It's all you, Chief.
Look at me, Dad.
- Hey, look at you. You're doin' it.
I'm doin' it.
- You're doin' it.
How's it feel?
- Good.
This is great.
- Look at your balance.
Like I'm on a flying trapeze.
- You're like a circus act.
This feels great.
- You're goin' around the world.
It's like flying.
- Wait till your mother sees this, huh?
Look at me.
- Let's wake up the world, huh?
Oh, my God.
Hello?
- John? John Sullivan?
It's me.
You're the voice of an angel.
Reached right outta heaven
and you pulled my butt outta the fire.
Tell me I'm not dreamin' here.
Tell me it's really you.
It's me, John.
This ain't no dream.
But how could it be?
- I don't know. I don't know...
but we gotta be talkin' off
the mother sunspot of all time.
Yeah, I'd say so.
You okay, Chief?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You sure?
It's tough to explain.
I mean, I got all these new memories,
but I don't know what to believe.
What do you mean?
'Cause I still remember what it was
like when you died in the fire.
But I'm the only one.
I don't understand what
you're talkin' about.
I remember both at the same time.
It... It's like wakin' up from a dream,
and you're not sure what's real.
I remember you bein' here,
but I also remember when you weren't.
Oh, I'm sorry, John.
I'm sorry. I never thought that...
- Well, you gotta think about that.
And you gotta be more careful,
'cause I can't lose you again.
Not like that.
You won't, John, you won't.
I swear to God, no matter what,
not like that.
You got it? You hear me?
You hear me, Chief?
- I hear you.
So how old are you?
I'm 36.
- Thirty-six?
Well, you're all grown up.
You gotta be married and everything.
No, I'm not married.
Why? What are you,
too busy playin' ball?
No, uh, it didn't work out.
I gave it up.
What happened?
I just blew my arm out my senior year...
and didn't have a shot.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Johnny.
I know that had to hurt.
Yeah, thanks.
So, what'd you wind up doing?
You join the department?
Actually, I went the other way.
I'm a cop.
You're third-generation firefighter.
Come on, I thought you were gonna
grow outta that cop phase.
Well, you got Satch to
thank for that one.
You gotta be kiddin' me, huh?
Satch?
Well, he always was crazy about you
ever since you were born.
You're still my Little Chief.
Right?
Yeah, I'm tryin' to be.
I'm tryin'.
Well, tell me about yourself.
Tell me about your life.
I mean, where do I start,
you know?
Mustang?
I don't own a Mustang.
Well, you will.
And you loved it.
Fire-engine red.
- Yeah?
Four on the floor.
- Seventy home runs?
That's a record that'll
never be broken.
I wouldn't be too sure.
The other guy hit 66.
Really? You mean, like those
big field radios you use in the army?
No, much smaller.
Works off a satellite or something.
You carry it around in your pocket.
Hey, what about Apollo?
How'd it all work out?
It was a great Series, Pop.
Amazing.
So we win, right?
- Hold your horses. I'm gettin' there.
Game three. Agee came through,
homered off Palmer in the second.
I knew it. I knew Agee
was gonna have a great Series.
Forget about Agee. Wait until you hear
what happened to Cleon Jones.
You sound like your mother.
- Nah, I'm serious.
Oh, come on. Your grandfather...
he smoked, what, two packs a day.
He's still kickin'.
- Not you.
It's gonna get the better of you.
Okay?
Well, I just knew.
She melted my heart.
That was it.
You got anybody?
Yeah, kinda.
There's somethin' I gotta work out, but...
she's worth it.
No, you, um, go ahead.
You, uh, get some rest.
I'm... I'm tired too.
I almost don't wanna click off here like...
maybe we won't get this back.
We will.
- Okay.
I'll be here tomorrow.
I know.
I love you, son.
I...
I love you, too, Dad.
I've...
I've missed you so much.
Hi, this is Julia Sullivan.
Please leave a message after the tone.
Hey, Ma, it's me.
Just call me.
We gotta talk.
Take over for me?
- All right.
Frank, what's going on?
- Nothin'. Just wanted to see you.
Yeah?
I'm not goin' anywhere, Jules.
Not for the rest of your life.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
I got a bad feeling today.
I was worried.
Hmm? Look at me. Not a scratch.
- Where's Johnny?
He's at Gordo's.
I tucked him in.
You give him his drops?
- One in each ear.
What would you do without me?
Probably marry some rich doctor.
Never have to work.
Oh, my God. What is he doin'?
Frank, I gotta...
Excuse me, Doctor.
Is that benazepril?
I gave this patient 50 mils of Benadryl
on admittance. Mix them, and he's dead.
Why wasn't I made aware of this?
- It's in his chart.
Hello, Ma?
- Noah's Deli.
I'm sorry.
This is Noah's Deli.
Sam, I gotta talk to you.
- Excuse me?
Look, I'm sorry,
but I gotta talk to you.
How do you know my name?
Who are you?
- Who am I?
Look, I don't know you.
You don't know me?
What do you mean, you don't know me?
Wait. I do know you.
You're Linda and Gordo's friend.
The neighbor, the cop.
What are you doin' here?
I shouldn't have come here.
I didn't mean to upset you.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I'll take care of it.
What?
- Another rough night?
Is that it?
- Yeah, that's it.
Do not disrespect me, John.
Disrespect yourself all you want to,
but not me or anybody else here.
Got that?
We got the preliminary forensics
on the skeleton.
Take a look at this.
Bad memories.
Can you imagine the odds of digging
up a Nightingale murder?
She makes ten.
- Ten?
No. I remember this case.
It was three. He killed three women.
What are you talkin'?
You know better than anybody, John.
You looked through these files
a thousand times.
No.
Dad? You there?
Can you hear me?
Dad, I need you to be there.
Yeah, Chief, I'm comin'.
Listen, there's something I need to t...
Right here.
Chief?
Something happened.
Something pretty bad.
What's the matter, Johnny?
Mom. Something happened to her.
- Your mom. What?
She's not here.
What do you mean, she's not there?
She died. But it's like
it just happened though.
She died? Your mom just died?
No, Dad. It happened a long time ago.
A long time ago for me.
When?
October 22, 1969.
That's now, Johnny.
That's next week.
How? You gotta tell me how.
She was murdered.
- What are you talking about?
Listen to me.
There was this case.
A serial. They never caught him,
but he murdered three women.
All nurses between '68 and '69.
They call him the Nightingale.
The Nightingale? We've been watching it
on the news. I was worried about it.
Dad, we did something.
Something to make it worse.
I don't understand.
He didn't just kill three women any more.
He's killed ten.
Something we did changed the past.
But how come your mother...
- Just think about it.
Everything you did is different than if
you hadn't gotten out of that warehouse.
Now, what'd you do last night, Dad?
I talked to you.
I put you on the bike.
I tucked you in at Gordo's. I went
to see your mother at the hospital.
Oh, shit. That's it.
She wasn't supposed to be there.
Butch went and got her because
that was the night of the fire.
Something happened at that hospital?
It could have been anywhere or time that
she wouldn't have been if you'd died.
I have to take her away from here.
He cannot hurt her if I take her.
- What about the others?
What about the others?
- I'll warn them.
They'll just think you're crazy.
I gotta do something. You don't
even know what this guy looks like.
No, because... No, but...
- You don't know who he is.
Wait a minute.
Dad, I may not know who he is...
but I know where he's gonna to be and
what he's gonna do before he gets there.
Do I call the police?
They won't believe me.
They will if they catch him in the act.
And you can make that happen.
No, I don't know about...
I'm a firefighter.
I'm a cop. This is what I do.
This is something we have to do.
What if the ham stops working?
What if I can't reach you?
Then get Mom out.
But, Dad, those other women
were not supposed to die.
If we don't try and stop this guy...
we'll have to live with that
for the rest of our lives.
Okay. Tell me what to do.
- All right.
The next victim is Carrie Reynolds.
It happens tomorrow. Case file says
she left Roosevelt Hospital at 6:00.
Showed up at Cozy's Bar around 6:30.
She walked out of that bar around 7:30.
And they found her dead in an alley
behind the bar at 8:00.
Follow her. See if anybody's
watching her or hitting on her.
I'm betting when she walks out of
that place, somebody'll go out with her.
When they do, you call the cops.
Hi, Carrie.
- Hiya, Glen. How you doin'?
Real good.
From the girls, pal.
All of them.
Thanks.
Sit down.
- A fireman, huh?
Yeah, I'm not really...
- Ah, a married fireman.
Yeah.
- What the hell. What do they call you?
Frank.
7-4. Homicide.
Yeah, it's me.
You're kiddin'.
Hold on. Spell that for me.
Okay. Thanks, Mario.
Our lucky break.
Mario ID'd the dental.
Her name's Mary Finelli.
Reported missing April 16, 1968.
April 16?
That means she was the first.
Which means he probably knew her.
This case just got hot.
She's gone.
Carrie Reynolds isn't in here.
Who?
He did it.
Carrie Reynolds is alive and well, Dad.
I'll be damned.
- Did you see him?
Figure who he is?
- No, I messed up.
I kept talking to her.
I was afraid to let her out of my sight.
Whoever it was,
he must've backed off.
That's okay. We're gonna get him.
This is gonna work.
I hope so.
What else you got?
- We caught a break.
Found his first victim.
Her name is Mary Finelli.
Hang on a sec, John.
Jules, there's somebody
I want you to talk to, okay?
Remember I told you about this guy John?
I want you to say hello to him.
John, say hello to my wife, Julia.
Hi, John.
Frank tells me you're a cop.
Yeah, that's right.
My six-year-old keeps telling us
he wants to be a policeman...
right after he retires from the majors.
We bought him a badge and whistle
for his birthday.
I remember.
I used to play cops and robbers...
but you... my mom wouldn't let me
have a toy gun.
Sounds like your mom and I
would get along.
Yeah, she's pretty special.
I'm real proud of her.
Bet she's proud of you, too,
being a cop and all.
I hope so. I hope she knows
how much I love her.
Oh, she knows. Moms always know
how much their kids love them.
Even if they don't tell them
all the time like they should.
Well, I gotta go.
It was good talking to you, John.
Yeah, you too.
I wanna talk on Daddy's radio.
- Okay, Chief, go ahead.
Sweetheart, say good night to John.
- Good night, John.
Good night there, Chief.
Okay, guys. Bedtime.
No, I wanna talk on the radio, too.
All right, Gordo, come here.
- Gordo, two minutes, then bedtime.
Sit right there.
Press there.
This is the space cowboy.
I'm an intergalactic traveler
from the federation planet Earth.
Gordo?
- How do you know my name, mister?
Listen, Gordo...
my name is Santa Claus.
And I'm going to give you the
biggest Christmas present you ever had.
I better give you my address then.
No, don't worry about it.
Now, this is important.
Something you got to remember
for a long time. Yahoo.
What's that?
It's a magic word. It's like...
It's like abracadabra, but even better.
Try it out, kid. Yahoo.
Yahoo.
- You got it, space cowboy.
Gordo, your two minutes are up.
Now go upstairs and write it down.
- Okay, mister.
I mean, Santa.
- Come on.
Let's go. Stay there, John.
I'll be right back. Upstairs.
Jules, got a live one down here
coming your way.
Yeah, Chief?
You still there?
What do we do now?
- Okay, Sissy Clark.
423 Greenwich Street.
- Hang on, hang on. Go ahead.
Sissy Clark, 423 Greenwich Street,
apartment 2E, tomorrow.
Okay, 2E.
- Nurse.
Moonlights as a cocktail waitress
at the Kaleidoscope on West 63rd.
Left work at 2 a. m...
was killed in her apartment
between 2:15 and 5:00.
Okay, I got it.
Dad, I don't know how long
this thing is gonna keep workin'.
Or if we'll be able to talk again.
Just be careful.
I'm happy you found her, Detective.
It makes it easier now,
to know for sure.
You know.
Can I keep these for a while?
Okay, just let me walk you through it.
I'm all ears.
Three guys show up
in both the yearbook and diary.
First guy passed away ten years ago.
Second guy died in Vietnam.
And the third one is Daryl Simpson.
So I ran him through BCI.
Got a hit.
Busted for sexual assault eight days
after the last Nightingale murder.
March 22, 1970.
So the murders stopped because
he was off the street...
and by the time he got paroled he had
smartened up enough to control himself?
That's not the first time that's been true.
I got a feeling about this guy.
This is him, Satch.
Can I get you another one?
- No thanks, I'm good.
Anything else?
Sexual assault, Daryl.
Five years.
But you got lucky, right?
You got away with something else.
Something you figured
nobody knows about.
What I know is what I told you.
Let me tell you what I know.
You went to Saint Ambrose with Mary.
You lived five blocks from her.
You liked her, but she ain't interested.
That must've hurt, huh?
- So what?
So, what'd you do about it?
- Nothing.
Spare a smoke?
Yeah.
Here, I'm trying to quit.
Oh, my God.
What is this?
Jesus. Jesus.
Get that away from me.
- Sandra Moore. Patty Ryan.
Mary Finelli. These names
mean anything to you?
Julia Sullivan.
Does she mean anything?
Well, she means something to me.
See ya, fireman.
Don't talk so much next time.
Will you run my tips while I go change?
Thanks.
You know, Daryl...
sometimes, despite all the training
we cops go through...
despite all that we are taught
about right and wrong...
despite all that we would like
to honor in ourselves...
we can come to a place...
where we don't give a damn.
Know what I mean?
You'll tell me everything
I need to know now.
You got a minute?
Yeah, sure.
He ain't the guy, John.
Because he didn't want to look at the
photos? Not everyone fits the profile.
If he was gonna give up something,
he would've done it already.
You following me?
I asked you a question, asshole.
Mary Finelli.
Whoa, dude.
What happened to him?
It was a bad trip, man. A little time
kissing the porcelain, he'll be fine.
I understand that.
- All right, come on, pal.
Open up.
Miss Clark. Open the door.
It's the police. Open the door.
It's okay, ma'am. Go back inside.
It's the police.
Are you in there? Open up.
I know you're in there.
Sissy Clark. Open the door.
Open the door.
He killed her.
I couldn't do a damn thing to stop it.
It's not your fault.
- Yes, it is.
We changed everything, Johnny.
It's like we cheated.
- Dad, we can't go back.
'Cause you didn't die in that fire.
No matter what you do,
nothing is going to change it.
So all we can do is deal with this
and try to make it right.
I'm not a cop. I'm not fooling anyone.
- I know, but we can.
We can do it together.
Remember spirit and guts?
He's got my driver's license.
What?
He took my driver's license.
He knows where we live.
He took your...
He took your wallet?
Well, he tossed the wallet,
but he kept the license.
He touched your wallet? Where is it?
- In my pocket.
We got him, Dad. You got him.
- What?
You got his prints. Listen,
you gotta get me that wallet.
How the hell am I supposed to do that?
- As carefully as possible.
Take your wallet out by the corners.
- What are you talking about?
Dad, just do it.
- All right.
All right. Right. Okay.
I got it.
All right, listen.
I want you to wrap it up.
Put it in one of them plastic bags
you keep the extra transistors in.
I see where you're going.
Beautiful. Now, I want you
to hide it somewhere.
Somewhere where nobody's
gonna find it for the next 30 years.
I think maybe...
- Where?
The window seat in the dining room.
There's a loose board on the left,
on the bottom.
Perfect. Beautiful.
It's in.
Great. Okay, I'm after it.
We're in business.
Now just sit tight and don't worry.
And the winner is...
Oh, man. It's a cop.
What the hell?
Son of a bitch.
Hey, Mr. Shepard. How are you?
Who's that?
Oh, hi, Detective.
I came by to wrap things up over there.
Thought I'd say hello.
I'm glad you did.
Come on in.
Thank you.
Buy you a cup of coffee?
- Sure.
Black? Sugar? Milk?
- Oh, you know. It's all good.
You'll get black.
Fresh pot.
You know Jack?
- Not really.
He's still on the job?
He does a little P.I.,
but he's mostly retired.
Living off his pension, huh?
Jack got caught up
in them Knapp hearings.
Set up by some dirty cops
who needed a fall guy.
Hurt him bad.
Would've broke his mother's heart.
Is she around?
- Who?
Your wife.
- No. She passed on a long time ago.
Long time ago.
I'm sorry.
- Oh, that's okay.
Can I ask you how she died?
Well, she...
She was murdered.
An ugly one, to tell you the truth.
Mother of a cop, and they never found
the bastard who did it.
You on the job?
A long time ago.
Do I know you?
- I look familiar?
What house you work?
- The 7-4. Homicide.
Mmm, a hotshot.
No, just working the job.
- Yeah, I hear that, pal.
As a matter of fact, I caught a case
that goes back to your day.
One of the Nightingale murders.
No kidding?
- No. Missing teenager.
Disappeared back in '68.
We found her bones last week...
buried behind some old diner
out by Dyckman Street.
Mary Finelli.
Talk about dumb luck.
The odds of finding that girl 30 years
later and of hitting a dental...
Forget about it.
The best part is,
she's the first victim.
And she knew the killer, so...
I'm betting those old bones
are gonna do a lot of talking.
But not for nothing.
The past is a funny thing.
We all have skeletons in the closet.
You never know when they're going
to pop up and bite you in the ass.
Huh, Jack?
You changed your M.O.
If they knew your mom was a Nightingale,
they would've looked at the family.
They would've looked at you.
And what are you lookin' at?
Stealin' your life away.
You went down 30 years ago, pal.
You just don't know it yet.
A cop? He's a cop? What the hell
am I supposed to do with that?
Call the FBI. Use a pay phone.
Don't give him your name, Dad.
Say Shepard killed Finelli, Clark and
the others. That he's the Nightingale.
Say where Finelli's body's buried.
They'll connect him to her.
Frank here?
- They'll search his place.
They'll find some souvenirs. He always
took a piece of his victims' jewelry.
Satch.
- Hey, Frank.
What are you doing here? Are you off?
- We need to talk.
Dad?
- Hang on a sec, John.
I'm in the middle of something important
here. Mind if we do this...
I'm sorry, Frank, but we need
to step outside right now.
What's happening?
John, Satch is here.
He's with his partner.
- What's going on?
Hang on a sec.
What's your partner doing here?
- What happened to your eye?
Banged it up.
Let's talk outside.
We need to do that.
- About what?
Let's go. Do us both a favor.
- All right.
Stay there. I'll be back.
Be right back, all right?
So where were you last night, Frank?
Where do you think I was, Satch?
Same place I found this.
Under the body of a dead woman.
No, this isn't what you think.
This isn't what you think.
- I want to be wrong.
So let's take a ride down
to the precinct and talk about it.
Yeah, I need to talk to you, too.
- Come on, we'll take a ride.
All right. Let me tell my family
where I'm going.
All right? Be right back.
It's all right.
Don't worry.
Chief, you there?
- Yeah.
They found Sissy Clark.
They think that I did it.
Frank.
- Give me a second.
Don't do this.
What's going on?
- Uncle Satch, don't.
He's a cop.
A cop.
Jack Shepard.
He's a detective in the 15th precinct.
I swear, Satch.
And you got all this from the guy on
the radio, from your son in the future.
Yeah. As nuts as that sounds, yeah.
You've gotta listen to me, open up your
mind and try to understand what I say.
You got something going on
with this girl, that's one thing.
But you gotta tell me.
Are you listening to me?
You're in a world of shit.
An eyewitness puts you outside
the dead girl's apartment.
Your prints are all over the place,
not to mention the license.
Chuck is getting a search warrant
for your house.
What's he going to find, huh?
- Nothing.
Give me something,
something I can believe.
It's number five for Dave McNally.
Two Mets are out in the fifth inning.
What if I can prove it to you?
How's that?
World Series. Where are they
right now? What? Fifth inning?
What if I were to tell you...
that in the bottom
of the sixth inning...
the Mets are gonna be down three-zip?
Cleon Jones is gonna come to bat.
He's going to get hit...
in the foot by a wild pitch.
It's gonna leave a shoe polish mark
on the ball.
Hear me out.
Hear me out, all right?
He goes to first.
Clendenon comes up.
He's gonna hit a two-two pitch
into the left field bleachers.
This is insane.
In the bottom of the seventh,
Weis is gonna hit a solo home run...
and Jones and Swoboda
are gonna score in the eighth.
The Mets are gonna win that game,
five to three.
Go watch that game.
If it don't happen, I'm a liar.
Go watch the game?
- Yeah, watch the game.
Frank, they're gonna make you
for Sissy Clark's murder.
And they're gonna match that
with the Nightingale murders.
Do you understand what that means?
His wife is here.
She wants to talk to you.
Let's walk, Jules.
Get a cup of coffee.
How you doin'?
You got a collar in here
for the Nightingale murders?
Yeah.
Everything okay with you and Frank?
Yeah, we're good. He works hard.
I work hard. We're good.
Who's Sissy Clark, Satch?
Do you know where Frank was last night?
Yeah, he was working. He had a tour.
Sit down.
Did you hear what I said?
So how'd you know?
Hey, this guy tried...
- How you doin'?
What's happening?
Shut up, asshole.
Mind if we take this outside?
He's trying to kill me.
Find Satch. He's trying to kill me.
What are you doing with my collar?
Listen, I'm sorry, pal.
I didn't mean to step on your toes.
They sent me from downstairs.
I thought you'd be with him.
What are you looking at him for?
He matches a description
of an armed robbery suspect.
So tell me about the radio.
Who's he talking to on that thing?
John. He's a cop.
He talks to him all the time.
I've talked to him, too.
You talk to Johnny on the radio?
- Yeah. John. What's going on?
You come and take Frank and now
you're talking to me like a cop.
I'm talking to you as a friend.
'Cause as a cop I wouldn't be here at all.
Listen, Jules...
they're gonna take me off this case.
And then Frank is gonna tell them
what he's been tellin' me.
And then nobody is gonna
be able to help him. Okay?
Cleon Jones makes the catch.
Half the uniforms are at the game.
It'll be a riot if they pull it off.
What is he telling you?
That he's talking to Johnny on the radio.
Yeah. John, the cop.
I told you that.
No, he says that John...
is your son, Johnny, little Johnny...
on the radio in the future.
On the radio. You see?
No. You misunderstood him.
Sissy Clark?
- Yeah.
She's a nurse.
And she was murdered yesterday.
And Frank is connected.
He is either a material witness
or accomplice or the perpetrator.
McNally, who's been thoroughly
in command.
Cleon starts down to first base,
and DeMiro calls him back.
Satch, you know he didn't do this.
Right?
Carrying the baseball,
he's coming over now.
Hodges showing the baseball to DeMiro.
- Can I see him?
Hodges... We might have
a shoe polish play here.
Remember the Nippy Jones shoe polish
play in the 1957 World Series...
at Milwaukee?
Hodges showing it to DeMiro,
who awards first base.
My God.
Satch, what's going on?
Mind if I go back at the fireboy?
I wanna see what he's got.
Jesus.
It's out down here.
Hey, bud.
Go ahead.
See if aviation's got a helicopter...
for commencing an air search
for body in water.
It was a season and World Series for the
ages for the Mets and MVP Don Clendenon.
For the Mets faithful,
the New York fans, wow.
Here's your coffee and cigarettes.
I'll be upstairs.
Incredible sun storm has created
a remarkable aurora borealis.
A cold front, and the aurora is already
dimming and will be over by morning.
John, are you there?
John, I'm back.
- I'm here, Dad.
We did it, son.
- What?
We stopped him.
- We did?
Yeah.
There's something... Something's wrong.
I don't...
What's wrong?
If we stopped him,
why isn't Mom here?
Why don't I remember her being okay?
But I killed him. He's dead.
My turn to steal...
your life away.
John? Johnny, you there?
Hey, bud.
Julia.
Mommy?
No.
Hey, Johnny.
It's okay, it's okay.
What are you gonna do, Frank?
Put the gun down.
Let him go.
You put the gun down.
I'll snap his neck.
Put the gun down now.
Time to die, Sullivan.
Time to die.
Run, Johnny, run, run, run.
Run.
Come here. You all right?
You all right?
I'm still here, Chief.
'Round the horn, 'round the horn.
Come on, new batter,
new batter, new batter.
Come on, Frank.
The Benz. Not the Benz.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Nice hittin', Frank.
Way to go.
Thank you very much.
Let's play some ball.
Come on.
New batter, new batter, new batter.
Go get it.
He's slow. He's old.
Come on, Johnny.
- Bring me home, Chief.